livejapan.com 2019-12-17

# Privacy Policy｜Gurunavi, Inc.

## Our Philosophy regarding Personal Information Protection

In utilizing personal information, which is essential in order to pursue our business activities, we the Gurunavi Group (the "Company Group") fully recognize the importance of and our social responsibility for appropriately protecting such personal information, and we will comply with the Act on the Protection of Personal Information and other relevant laws and ordinances. In addition, we have established a "Personal Information Protection Management System", internal company rules that ensure confidentiality and appropriate handling of personal information. All employees comply with the system in accordance with personal information protection policies.

## Personal Information Protection Policy

1\. Handling of Personal Information

We will handle personal information in a legal and fair manner, taking into account the content and size of our business. We will indicate to you the purpose of utilization and will not use any personal information for any purpose other than the purpose indicated to you.

2\. Compliance with Laws, Ordinances, and Standards

We will comply with the laws, ordinances, policies, and other standards, customs and social rules in Japan and any other countries and regions.

3\. Appropriate Measures for Personal Information Management

We will take measures to securely manage personal information, endeavoring to prevent the leakage, destruction, damage, loss, falsification, or illegal access of personal information. We will constantly seek to improve in this area.

4\. Organized Activities for Personal Information Protection

  1. (1)

We will designate a personal information manager and establish a Personal Information Protection Management System. The personal information manager is granted the authority and responsibility to implement and manage the System in the course of our operations.

  2. (2)

We will improve internal rules and operations based on the results of internal inspections.

  3. (3)

The Policy will be available to the public via our website and other means.

5．Continuous Improvement

  1. (1)

We will regularly reevaluate our "Personal Information Protection Management System" to establish, implement, maintain, and improve our measures for appropriate personal information protection.

  2. (2)

We will endeavor to train and educate our employees in personal information protection so that they can recognize the importance of personal information protection and appropriately manage and handle personal information.

  3. (3)

We may change the Policy to better protect personal information we have obtained or to make the Policy compliant with amendments of laws, ordinances, and other rules, as well as taking into account our customers' opinions. If we make any changes to the Policy, we will announce it by publishing the changes on our website and the like.

6\. Complaints, Opinions, and Other Enquiries about Personal Information

Please send any complaints, opinions, or enquiries regarding our handling of your personal information (specific personal information) using the "Complaints, opinions, or enquiries regarding personal information (specific personal information)" link at the bottom of the page. We will appropriately and promptly respond to you within a reasonable period and to a reasonable extent.

## Handling of Personal Information

1\. Purpose of use of personal information

Purpose of Utilization of Personal Information Category | Purpose of Utilization  
---|---  
Customers' Personal Information | 

  * •To confirm a person’s identity (including biometric identification) when registering an account with or logging into services provided by the Company Group, and for the Company Group to provide said services
  * •Contacting and informing customers via phone, mail, email etc. about the Company Group's services. Distributing questionnaire surveys and email newsletters
  * •To conduct surveys which include answers related to personal information of the participant; when contacting the participant with information about the products and services of the Company Group; in sales activities towards the participant including the promotion of events
  * •Restaurant reservation procedures, reservation management, contacting customers, ascertaining number of customers coming to restaurant, customer identity verification upon arrival at restaurant, and provision of personal information to the reserved restaurant
  * •Providing our services, ascertaining and analyzing customers' usage of our services by using customers' visiting, purchase, page-view, and activity history (hereafter "history") or location information
  * •To create statistical data such that an individual cannot be identified based on their appearance and use this data to ascertain and analyze circumstances of customer visits and improve the quality of the Company Group’s services
  * •Sending recommendations and direct mail to customers based on their history
  * •Settlement and repayment of fees, points, and other payments (we may exchange our customers' personal information with cell phone service providers, credit card companies, and the like)
  * •To inform customers about seminars, exhibitions, campaigns, competitions and the like (hereafter "events") held or co-held by the Company Group; in the participation in and application procedures for such events and in related lotteries and prize distribution; to ascertain information on participation in, and to organize/manage and conduct administrative work relating to such events. Images, videos, and sound recordings may be made at events. Personal information may also be provided to co-organizers of events, in the delivery of prizes and to a contractor entrusted with said delivery
  * •Reporting customers' feedback and requests to restaurants, wedding venues, commercial facilities, beauty salons, event promoters, hotels and the like, and product distributors
  * •Providing information on other companies' services introduced by the Company Group, acting as an intermediary for applications for such services, and administration and contact regarding the services
  * •Identity verification necessary for provision of the Company Group's services, delivery of various notices, administrative processes including fee charging, and confirmation of validity of materials used for customer identity verification
  * •The delivery of products or foodstuffs by the Company Group, its partner companies, organizations, producers and the like, and the creation of documents for use in delivery of goods
  * •The delivery of rewards for participation in market research surveys and promotions conducted by the Group Company
  * •Customer guidance and consulting via phone, email, or in person
  * •Audio and video recording to improve the quality of dealing with and responding to customers
  * •

The following agency operations:  
\- 

Registration, application, reservation, application management and other operations in all services

\- 

The sending of e-mails or messages over social media for promotional purposes

\- 

Applications and other procedures under government systems

  * •Delivery, installation, construction, and initial setup of machinery to provide the Company Group's services, communication regarding delivery dates and other matters, and provision of personal information in the case that a contractor is entrusted with work
  * •Provision of guidebooks, members' magazines, VIP-only information and the like of the Company Group's services
  * •Production of information magazines, communications relating to and the conducting of interviews, and promotion and advertisement of the Company Group's business
  * •To research and analyze how the Company Group’s services are used and gauge customer satisfaction levels, to create statistical data such that a specific individual cannot be identified, and, through the use of this data, improve the Company Group’s marketing, website creation, development of new services, and quality of current services
  * •Corrections or deletions to information registered with the Company Group's services
  * •Confirmation of video recorded to serve and monitor activities of customers who visit our offices
  * •Maintenance of security of the Company Group's services, investigation, reporting, and contact in the event of an incident or accident

Personal Information Obtained for Compliance with Laws and Ordinances | 

  * •Exercise of rights under agreements or laws in relation to the Company Group's service, responding to claims, and appropriate implementation of business

Personal Information Obtained from Public Information Sources | 

  * •The Company Group's business activities including the provision of products and services, and notifying customers of events
  * •Transaction screening and credit management/check

Personal Information Obtained During Recruiting Activities | 

  * •Consideration of new employees joining the Company Group, contacting candidates regarding job interviews, notifying candidates of the results of job interviews, delivery of relevant recruitment documents, settlement of expenses
  * •The Company Group's overall employment activities, and provision of personal information to a third party in the case that a third party is entrusted with a portion of the work

Personal Information of Current and Former Employees | 

  * •Labor management
  * •Communication with, and provision of personal information to, affiliates, companies receiving secondees, and the like
  * •Payment of salaries, bonuses, and the like
  * •Filing of notices or reports to governmental agencies
  * •Communication for various purposes advertisement via paper, e-mail, or audio-visual means
  * •Emergency contact and practice notices for and sharing of results thereof
  * •Sales and support activities using voice, image, and video communication
  * •Ascertaining circumstances and contacting individuals following employee introductions during hiring periods
  * •Replies to surveys requested by other companies
  * •Registration of biometric information (veins etc.) with biometric equipment, confirmation of activities, video recording for crime prevention

Personal Information of Shareholders | 

  * •Delivery of our business reports or any other documents distributed to shareholders and the like
  * •Providing notices to and exchanging information with shareholders
  * •Responding to shareholders exercising their rights
  * •Management of shareholders in accordance with relevant laws and ordinances
  * •Provision of personal information for exercise of rights and performance of obligations in accordance with the Companies Act

Enquiry | 

  * •Any enquiries relating to the above

2\. Provision of personal information

2-1 Provision of personal information

When providing personal information, the Company Group takes measures to avoid providing personal information to any third party without your consent except in the following cases:

  1. (1)

Cases in which the provision of personal information is required by laws and ordinances

  2. (2)

Cases in which the provision of personal information is necessary for the protection of the life, body or property of an individual, and for which your consent is difficult to obtain

  3. (3)

Cases in which the provision of personal information is particularly necessary for improving public health or promoting the sound development of children, and it is difficult to obtain your consent

  4. (4)

Cases in which the provision of personal information is necessary for cooperating with a state organ or a local government, or those entrusted by the state organ or local government in executing the affairs prescribed by laws and ordinances, and in which obtaining your consent is likely to impede the execution of such affairs

  5. (5)

Cases in which we entrust the handling of personal data in whole or in part within the scope necessary for the achievement of the specified purpose of utilization

  6. (6)

Cases in which we provide personal data as a result of succeeding to a business due to a merger or other event, and the acquirer uses such personal data within the scope of the purpose of utilization before the succession

  7. (7)

Cases in which personal data is jointly used between the Company Group and a specific entity or individual, and in advance we notify, or make readily available to, you the following matters, or similar details of equal or greater scope 

    * •Joint use of personal data
    * •Purpose of utilization of an entity or individual using personal data
    * •Items of personal data to be jointly used
    * •Name or company name responsible for the management of personal data
    * •Scope of entities or individuals jointly using personal data
    * •Method of obtainment

2-2 Provision of information of officers and shareholders of corporations and other entities

We may provide information regarding the officers and shareholders of corporations or other organizations that is included in the information of such corporation or other organization and that has already been disclosed or publicly announced under laws and ordinances or by such person or such corporation or other organization, after obtaining the person's consent and notifying the person of the purpose of utilization.

2-3 Supervision of contractors

When we entrust the performance of services involving the handling personal information, we execute an agreement with the contractor regarding personal information protection, and exercise appropriate supervision or other control over the contractor to ensure the prevention of leakage, destruction, damage, loss, falsification, or illegal access of personal information or other divulgement of personal information.

3\. Activity History, Attribute Information, and Advertisement Delivery by a Third Party

  1. (1)

The Company Group may use cookies (and other similar technologies) in order to provide information that is easily accessible by, and more valuable to, customers.  
Cookies allow data to be temporarily saved on a computer or other devices used by a customer when accessing a web site. Using cookies enables us to acquire and save in the Company Group's server the customers' activity history in the Company Group's websites (including, but not limited to, URLs and content accessed and the order of access), and unidentifiable attribute information (by the combination of which an individual is not identifiable) such as age and sex, occupation, resident area, record of coming to the store, and location information.  
If you prefer not to allow us to collect your information, you can block cookies by modifying your internet browser preferences. Please contact your software manufacturer for instructions on how to change your browser settings. If you choose to block cookies, you may be unable to use a part of the Company Group's services such as the auto login function. 

  2. (2)

The Company Group uses advertisement delivery services provided by third parties. In providing advertisement delivery services, such third party may collect and use the information of customers' access history to the Company Group's website or activity history by using cookies.  
Cookies and other information acquired by such third party will be handled in accordance with its privacy policy.  
Customers may discontinue advertisement delivery performed by such third party using cookies by accessing an opt out page created on its website.

List of cookies used for activity history, attribute information, and advertisement delivery services provided by third parties

4\. Disclosure, etc. of Personal Information

4-1 Disclosure of retained personal data handled by the Company Group

  1. (1)

You may request the Company Group to notify you of the purpose of utilization of, disclose, correct, add or delete the content of, discontinue its utilization of, erase, or discontinue its provision to a third party of, the retained personal data handled by the Company Group ("disclosure, etc.") pursuant to the Act on the Protection of Personal Information. 

  2. (2)

When requesting notification of the purpose of utilization and disclosure, you are required to pay handling fees. (For handling fees, please refer to the "Fee and payment method for request for disclosure, etc.")

  3. (3)

You are required to pay all of the printing costs, costs of obtaining documents for identity verification, mailing costs and other costs.

  4. (4)

Please note that we only accept the request form designated by the Company Group, and do not accept any other request form.

  5. (5)

We will properly handle personal information acquired at the time of your request to the extent necessary for such request. Please understand that we do not return documents or other materials submitted (including documents for identity verification).

4-2 Fee and payment method for request for Disclosure, Etc

**In the case of request for disclosure and request for notification of the purpose of utilization:**

  1. (1)

Fee: 500 yen (including tax) per request.

  2. (2)

Payment method: Please enclose postage stamps worth 500 yen with the request form.

  * * Cost for replying in writing by simple registered mail
  * * If the cost of simple registered mail or the simple registered mail system is changed, the fee for request for Disclosure, Etc. will be changed accordingly.
  * * If the payment is either less than the specified fee amount or not enclosed, the Company Group will notify you thereof, and return all the submitted documents. You will be requested to resubmit the documents.
  * * Please understand that we do not accept requests by a person who visit our company in person.

4-3 Procedures for request

  1. (1)

Please download or print out the "Request form designated by the Company Group" indicated below.

  2. (2)

After filling out the relevant items in the form, and signing and sealing the form, please enclose the "documents for identity verification" and mail them to the "Personal Information (specific personal information) Enquiry Desk." In the case of a request made by an agent on your behalf, his or her address, signature and seal are required in addition to your address and name.

    1. **1)Request form designated by the Company Group**

[Request for disclosure, correction or deletion of personal information](https://c-corporate.gnst.jp/policy/pdf/sakujyo.pdf?201911261138) __  
[201KB, in Japanese]

* If we are not able to proceed with the procedures because the request form leaves out necessary items or includes misprints or other imperfections, the Company Group will notify you thereof at the address indicated in the written request. Please understand that if we do not receive resubmission of the documents (including undelivered mail) within 2 weeks from such notification, we will deem that you have not requested any disclosure, etc.

    2. **2)Documents for identity verification**

Please enclose copies of any two of the following. Please make sure that the copies clearly show your name and address.

      * •Valid driver's license (copies of both sides are required)
      * •Valid passport
      * •Copy of residence certificate (only relevant entries such as address and name, which do not include your domicile of origin or personal identification number)
      * •Certificate of insured person of an insurance (excluding medical records)

Notes

      * •If the present address is different from the address recorded with the Company Group due to change of address or for other reasons, please submit a copy of residence certificate showing the history of address change (which do not include your personal identification number)
      * •If we are unable to verify the identity because the documents for identity verification are either not enclosed or unreadable or for other reasons, the Company Group will notify you thereof, and return all the submitted documents. You are requested to resubmit the documents.
      * •If an agent delegated by you makes a request for disclosure, etc., we will confirm that he or she is your agent by the power of attorney to which your registered seal is attached and your certificate of seal impression, and the agent's document for identity verification, and if your statutory agent makes a request for Disclosure, Etc., we will confirm that he or she is your statutory agent by the statutory agent's document for identity verification and a document certifying the relationship between the statutory agent and you.

  3. (3)

Once we verify the identity, we will appropriately and promptly make a response within a reasonable period of time and to the reasonable extent. If we are not able to accept the request in part or full, we will provide a reason pursuant to the Act on the Protection of Personal Information.

## Specific Personal Information Protection Policy

1\. Name of Company

Company Group

2\. Compliance with Relevant Laws, Guidelines, etc.

Concerning the protection of specific personal information, the Company Group will comply with Japan’s laws, guidelines established by the national government, and other relevant standards (guidelines, etc.)

3\. Matters Related to Measures for Secure Management

The Company Group will establish appropriate internal rules and security measures to prevent the disclosure, destruction, damage, loss, falsification, unauthorized access, etc. of specific personal information.

4\. Appropriate Management of Specific Personal Information

The Company Group will work to ensure specific personal information is managed appropriately, implementing periodic inspections carried out by an appointed personal information manager.

5\. Consultation and Complaints Contact

We will appropriately and promptly respond to complaints, opinions, and questions regarding specific personal information handled by the Company Group within a reasonable period and to a reasonable extent.  
Please use the "Complaints, opinions, or enquiries regarding personal information (specific personal information)" link at the bottom of the page to contact us.

6\. Intended Use of Specific Personal Information

Personal information will only be used for purposes stipulated by Japan's laws, guidelines established by the national government, and other relevant standards (guidelines, etc.)

## Name of the Personal Information Manager (specific personal information)

Senior Managing Executive Officer Administration, Corporate Planning, Legal

## Complaints, Opinions, and Other Enquiries about Personal Information

Please contact us using the dedicated contact form or the following links:

  * ※Click here for enquiries regarding our handling of personal information.
  * ※Click here for enquiries regarding our handling of specific personal information.
  * ※Click here for enquiries regarding activity history and contextual information.
  * ※Please contact the following address for enquiries regarding the personal information we have obtained.

Personal Information Enquiry Desk:

Gurunavi, Inc.

1-2-2 Yurakucho, Chiyoda-ku, Tokyo, Japan 100-0006  
Complaint and Consultation Desk Manager at Personal Information Enquiry Desk

[Click here to make an enquiry.](https://ssl.gnavi.co.jp/company/english/contact/) __

## Company Group

In this Policy, the "Company Group" means the following companies.

  * •Gurunavi, Inc.
  * •Gurunavi Promotion Community Inc.
  * •Gurunavi Research Institute Inc.
  * •Gurunavi Support Associe, Inc.

  * *The information above will be periodically updated.

Gurunavi, Inc.  
Akio Sugihara, President, Representative Director

Personal information protection policy  
Established：July 1, 2004  
Last updated: August 1, 2019

Specific personal information protection policy  
Established：November 17, 2015  
Last updated: August 1, 2019
